Guide to the Mary Ellen Bute Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- June 2008 Addition, circa 1908-1983; 0.42; (1 box)
  - Passages from James Joyce's Finnegan's Wake, script, typescript, 1965 (Box 36, Folder 537)
  - Passages from James Joyce's Finnegan's Wake, story boards, undated (Box 36, Folder 538)
  - Lazarus Laughed, Act 2, script, draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 36, Folder 539)
  - Photographs (family photographs, most in Texas), 1920s, undated (Box 36, Folder 540)
  - Photographs of Mary Ellen Bute, circa 1908-1983 (Box 36, Folder 541)
  - Photographs and film fragments, possibly from Out of the Cradle Endlessly Rocking, 1970s (Box 36, Folder 542)
  - Program for the annual debutante Ball, Houston, Texas, 1927 (Box 36, Folder 543)
  - Notes on unidentified film productions, undated (Box 36, Folder 544)
  - "Abstract films," typescript, undated (Box 36, Folder 545)
  - "A Texas girl trips around the world," typescript, corrected, undated (Box 36, Folder 546)
  - "The boy who saw through," commentary, typescript, undated (Box 36, Folder 547)
  - Press release on Tarantella, typescript, undated (Box 36, Folder 548)
  - Press release on Rhythm in Light, typescript, undated (Box 36, Folder 549)
  - "Abstronics," reprint, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 550)
  - "Film music: New film music for new films," printed version, 1952 (Box 36, Folder 551)
  - "Philosophy of the kinetic art forms," typescript carbon, undated (Box 36, Folder 552)
  - "Plan for study IX: Requirements of an instrument for the free playing of kinetic color with form," typescript carbon, undated (Box 36, Folder 553)
  - Promotional material, undated (Box 36, Folder 554)
  - Review of Color Rhapsody, printed version, 1976 (Box 36, Folder 555)
- Oversize, 1.17; (1 box)
  - Graphics cards (Series I), undated (Box 34, Folder 517-519)
  - Abstract films, publicity and promotional material (Series I), 1953-1985, undated (Box 34, Folder 520)
  - "Out of the Cradle ...," clippings (Series I), 1975-1981, undated (Box 34, Folder 521)
  - "Out of the Cradle ...," clippings (Series I), undated (Box 34, Folder 522)
  - "Passages ....," promotional material (Series I), 1965-1966, undated (Box 34, Folder 523-524)
  - "Passages ...," clippings (Series I), 1965-1983, undated (Box 34, Folder 525-526)
  - Photographs (Series II), 1969, undated (Box 34, Folder 527)
  - "Mobilcolor" (Series IV), 1981-1982, undated (Box 34, Folder 528)
  - Promotional material (Series IV), undated (Box 34, Folder 529)
  - Clippings (Series V), undated (Box 34, Folder 530-531)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.21; (1 box)
  Box 35 contains fragile originals. Photocopies are provided for reference use. The material may be seen only with the permission of the appropriate curator.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 27, folder 402, 1962 (Box 35, Folder 532)
  - Box 18a, 1975-1977 (Box 35, Folder 533)